<title abbrev="SADI">SADI: Semantic Automated Data Integration</title>

<author initials='B.' surname='Vandervalk' fullname='Ben Vandervalk' role='editor'>
    <organization>James Hogg Research Centre, Institute for Heart + Lung Health, University of British Columbia</organization>
    <address>
        <!--
        <postal>
            <street>Meander 501</street>
            <street></street>
            <city>Arnhem</city> 
            <region></region>
            <code>6825 MD</code>
            <country>NL</country>
        </postal>
        -->
        <!-- <phone></phone> -->
        <email>ben dot vvalk at gmail</email>
        <!-- <uri></uri> -->
    </address>
</author>
<author initials='E.L.' surname='McCarthy' fullname='E. Luke McCarthy'>
    <organization>James Hogg Research Centre, Institute for Heart + Lung Health, University of British Columbia</organization>
</author>
<author initials='M.D.' surname='Wilkinson' fullname='Mark D. Wilkinson'>
    <organization>James Hogg Research Centre, Institute for Heart + Lung Health, University of British Columbia</organization>
</author>

<date month='January' year='2012' />

<area>General</area>
<workgroup>Submission by Individual</workgroup>
<keyword>Semantic Web</keyword>
<keyword>Web Services</keyword>
<keyword>RDF</keyword>
<keyword>OWL</keyword>
<keyword>SADI</keyword>
<abstract>
    <t>This memo describes a set of best practices called SADI for implementing stateless web services that natively consume RDF data as input and generate RDF data as output. Under SADI, the schemas for the input and output RDF data of a service are defined by the service's input OWL class and output OWL class, respectively. Metadata for a service, including the URIs of the input and output OWL classes, are retrieved by issuing an HTTP GET request to the service URL. SADI services are invoked by issuing an HTTP POST request to the service URL with an RDF document as the body of the request. The input RDF document may contain any number of instances of the input OWL class which represent independent inputs to the service. The service's response is an RDF document which contains a corresponding number of outputs which are instances of the output OWL class. Related instances of the input and output OWL classes always have the same root URI, in order to ensure that the data consumed and generated by a service are explicitly linked by one or more RDF triples.</t>
</abstract>
